4.36GB ; 1280x688 ; 23.976fps. ; x264 ; ac35.1,640kbps.
" Gothika " thriller-mystery , USA , 2003
" Gothika " thriller-mystery , USA , 2003 He came back again last night
He came back again last night and tore me like paper .
He opened me like a flower of pain
and it felt good .
He sank into me and set me on fire
like he always does .
Made me burn from the inside out .
How did you know it was the devil ?
I know what you 're thinking .
I know you think I 'm talking about my stepfather
because you don 't believe in the devil .
Okay , let 's talk about your stepfather .
You know about my stepfather . You know I cut his throat .
I cut his Adam 's apple in half
like a piece of fruit on a summer day
so he wouldn 't say a word .
I sat next to him and watched him die
slowly .
It was the only way to help him stop .
Stop what ?
Stop fucking me !
You 're not listening .
I am listening , Chloe .
You 're not listening with your heart . Just your brain .
Your brain is the problem .
You have no idea how it feels not to be trusted .
You 've got to trust me too , Chloe .
You can 't trust someone who thinks you 're crazy .
Okay . I think that 's enough for today .
But I do think we made some really good headway
found out some new things ...
Do you know what it is to burn from the inside ?
- Do you know ? Because you are dead ! - Let her go , Chloe .
I am . I 'm not touching her ! I 'm not touching her ! Let me go !
Let me go ! Let me go .
Thank you .
You 're driving me crazy ! Stop !
- Stop it ! - Let go !
Stop it !
I can walk by myself !
Stand up !
Look at that .
" I 'm a doctor . "
" Open this door . " Hey , you are dead !
Get in .
She 's nuts .
Hey .
Sorry .
I need to cross-reference some files with you on Monday . How 's your morning ?
- Check with Anna . She 'll fit you in . - Thanks . Sorry .
I 'm not discharging her , period .
If you want to pursue this , sir , have a judge order her transfer .
Until then she 's mine .
Thank you .
Lawyers .
Hey , come on in .
What 's up ?
Chloe . She 's embellishing her rape story again .
She says that the devil is visiting her in her cell .
- Okay . - Well , it 's the third time in three months .
It has something to do with her stepfather , possibly remorse
but instead of assessing the memory and accepting it
she just falls into these satanic meanderings .
Time . Give it time .
I 've given it time . Time and Elavil . And Mellaril and Haldol .
Maybe they 're just
too medicated .
I know we all create our realities to some extent . Yes , true .
But what she creates is so far from any objective reality ...
Chloe 's mind only runs on one track .
Well , right now , my mind is running on empty .
Come here .
You have a brilliant mind .
You 'll figure it out .
Throw it on the mirror .
This is what she sees now .
- A distorted image of herself . - Who are you in all this ?
- I 'm the mirror . - You are the mirror .
If I 'm the mirror and she 's the image
then who are you ?
I can see both of you
so I 'm God .
Or just an overworked hospital bureaucrat .
" God " is good .
Always remember , the ability to repress
is actually a vital survival tool . Without it
Chloe might not have survived .
Sorry , am I interrupting the happy couple ?
Dr. Graham . We were just discussing repression as a survival mechanism .
Oh , yeah , I had a date last week . I barely survived it . I 'm trying to forget it .
I 'm sure your amorous adventures are fascinating , doctor
but sadly , I 'm on my way out .
- Well , don 't let me ... I 'll just ... - No , no , no , I 'm leaving .
I 'm gonna run out to Willow Creek . Meet the new contractor .
I 'll be here . See you at dinner .
Keep an eye on my wife for me , Pete . I know you will . Here .
- No , thanks . - No , let me circumcise it for you .
Smoke it tonight while it 's fresh .
- Good night , boss . - Good night , kids .
Why don 't we share one of those golden-crust , cheese-filled specials .
- It sounds like a great offer ... - Here 's the file .
... but I got work to do . - I 'm buying .
- It 's cold when it gets here . - We could warm it up .
- I hate pizza . - Who doesn 't like pizza ?
Come on , you gotta eat .
Not with you .
Come on , we 're supposed to celebrate . I just got circumcised ...
- Who 's inside ? - We have Shelley for observation .
- Why ? What happened ? - She had another attack .
- What 'd you do , up her meds ? - Yeah , 25 milligrams .
That 's extreme . That dose is way too high .
I want a copy of that on my desk by Monday , okay ?
- Okay . - Thank you .
Damn generator .
Not again .
Irene , is that you ?
This electric system 's gonna give us trouble .
Fourth time this week . I 'm going for my swim .
Well , I 'm gonna do my job , as long as these damn lights stay on .
- Good night , Joe . - Hey , how many laps , doc ?
Fifty-five , but who 's counting ?
Oh , you 've outdone yourself . Hey , safe drive home .
- Thank you . Say hi to your wife for me . - Will do .
All that education but you can 't remember an umbrella .
- Did you get my note ? - Yeah , I got your note . Your business note .
Right . So how was your date with ?
With what 's-her-name ? It was like all of my dates . It was brief . It was pointless .
She didn 't respond to my sense of humor , my boyish good looks
so I started talking about work .
She said that was not a suitable topic for a first date
and that was it . I mean , it was just drinks , you know .
I mean , we didn 't even have dinner .
She 's not right . When you know , you know .
I know .
- I 'll follow you down the hill . - You don 't have to .
- No , I 'm supposed to keep an eye on you . - Since when did you ever listen to the boss ?
Severe showers all over northern Connecticut and New Hampshire .
- I know , I see that . - rain in Lennox County ...
- flooding throughout Lennox County and closure ...
- I can 't let you through . The road 's closed . - What 's going on ?
- I got this . - There 's a sinkhole .
- Hi , Bob . - You picked a hell of a night for a drive .
There 's a sinkhole up here , you can 't get through . Sorry .
- What should I do ? - Go a quarter of a mile down , take a left ...
You know that bridge that Doug and I fish at ?
- Yeah , the little white one ? - That 's the one .
- Yeah . - You can go across there .
- Okay , thanks . - Hey , tell Doug to give me a call .
Will do .
- Doug , you 're home ? - Yeah , where are you ?
I got detoured , so I 'll be home in a few minutes , okay ? How was Willow Creek ?
This rain is slowing the work down . It 's a big mess .
- Are you okay ? - Yeah .
Doug .
Doug !
Are you okay ?
Hey !
Oh , my God . Okay . Okay . Okay .
I 'm a doctor . I 'm gonna take you to the hospital . I 'm a doctor , honey .
I 'm gonna help you , okay ? You 're gonna be okay .
I 'm gonna help you , okay ?
Help me !
Somebody !
Dr. Graham !
You better tell me why I 'm in here , Irene .
She got up wild .
- Bring your ass back in here . - Give me 40 milligrams of Ativan .
- Get your hands off me . - Stay in the cell .
- Keep her off . - Restrain her .
Keep her off of me . Get off of me . Do you hear me ? Get off of me .
Hold on . Calm ...
What are you doing ? What are you doing to me ?
Thank you , nurse .
- Are you okay ? - Yeah , she calmed down .
This is so sad .
Miranda , this is very awkward .
I suppose that technically I shouldn 't even be treating you
but I managed to get the court to grant us a waiver until you 're transferred .
Anything we discuss is in strict confidence
and won 't go anywhere but this room .
How long have I been in here ?
Three days .
Why ? Why ?
You were admitted to our neurosurgical unit , you were seizing violently .
We did scans and they revealed left-sided weakness , numbness
severe frontal-lobe deficits .
You received Haloperidol , Ativan injections .
When you came out of it , we tested . You were negative for PCP .
But you were put in restraints for a day and a half so you wouldn 't injure yourself .
And then you basically went into a state of catatonia .
This is the first time I 've seen you lucid .
I wanna talk to my husband .
Where is he ? Where is he ?
You know , you 're the most logical person I know , bar none .
You rely only on the facts .
So why am I telling you this ?
You 're establishing my personality .
You think I 'm a rational person . You don 't think I 'm impulsive or emotional .
And following this pattern of analysis , we are about to discuss
a traumatic event which has rendered this psychological profile useless .
- You think I 'm in denial . - Don 't analyze yourself
just focus on remembering .
Miranda
what 's the last thing you remember ?
I remember Chloe .
I was having my Friday night session with Chloe .
How did that go ?
She was embellishing her rape story .
- I saw Doug . - Dr. Graham .
You were there .
When I went back to my office , I worked on Chloe 's file .
I decided to call it quits , I went down to the pool , had a swim , 55 laps
saw Joe , got my keys . Went to my car . You walked me to it .
- Yes . - But ...
- There was a detour . - Oh , hey , tell Doug ...
I had to go over the bridge , so I went over the bridge .
I wonder what else happened . Try to remember .
I got home .
I saw Doug . He was on the couch .
Try to remember .
There was a girl .
- Yeah , there was a girl . - No , there was no ...
Yeah , there was a girl .
- A girl at the bridge . - There was no report ...
- There was some kind of accident . - No .
- The girl was bloody . On the bridge ... - I want to ask you about Doug .
What 's the last thing you remember ?
Why are you asking about Doug ? I 'm telling you about a girl I saw .
Was there any trouble in your marriage ?
No , there was no trouble in my marriage .
And why are you using the past tense of the word ?
Miranda
you don 't remember anything about Doug ? Anything at all ?
Don 't tell me something 's wrong with Doug .
I have to tell you something . Something very difficult .
No , no , no ...
- Don 't tell me there 's something with Doug . - Miranda
Doug is dead .
You killed him .
- No ! No ! No ! - Orderly !
I didn 't .
- No , I didn 't . - Orderly !
I didn 't ! I didn 't do it ! No !
No ! No ! No , don 't do it !
- It 's okay . - I didn 't do it . I didn 't do it .
I 'm on your side .
One little bit more .
Rita . Let go .
It 's Dr. Grey .
Look it up . Don 't look at me like that .
I 'm the official champion again .
Hello , Miranda . Welcome .
You 're one of us now .
You know I don 't belong here , Chloe .
If you 're here , it must mean that you belong .
You are not a doctor in here .
And even if you tell the truth
no one will listen .
You know why ? Because you 're crazy .
And the more you try to prove them wrong
the crazier you appear .
You are invisible now .
Can you feel it ?
Don 't touch me .
Are you scared ?
No .
You should be .
I 'm dreaming .
Dream logic , primary process , that 's what this is .
I 'm dreaming . I 'm dreaming . I 'm dreaming .
I 'm dreaming . I 'm dreaming .
I 'm not crazy . I 'm dreaming .
Rise and shine , honey . It 's a new day .
I wanna talk to Pete .
You 'll see Dr. Graham all in good time , but now I want you to have some breakfast .
- Why are you doing this to me , Irene ? - I 'm just doing my job .
You don 't want me to get Jim to help me , now do you ?
Good girl . You 're doing good .
Come on , sweetheart , now it 's time for a shower .
Come on , honey , time to wash away your sins .
You 're a nut .
Yeah , it 's you . You .
Get away . Get away .
What 's your problem ?
I looked away for a second . It 's unacceptable .
It 's not your fault .
Patients always find a way to hurt themselves , if that 's what they want .
I never pegged her for a cutter , that 's all .
Neither did I.
Shelley says Chloe 's been threatening Miranda
so I put her in isolation for the day .
How is she ?
She 's a mess .
I can 't believe she 's lost it so quickly . I 've never seen that before .
She cut herself 35 times , a lot of blood , but it 's superficial .
- What was the implement ? - Probably a scalpel
though how anybody got it in there , I have no idea .
Hey , Tony . We 're fine .
Come on .
You think I did this to myself , don 't you ?
Did you ?
No .
Well , I don 't know .
Who would it be , then ? Would it be
Chloe , or ?
I don 't know .
By your own admission you have difficulty
distinguishing what 's reality from fantasy , so is it possible ?
Yeah , as a doctor , I understand why you think that .
But something is really happening to me .
What about this moment , right now ?
What about it ?
Is this a hallucination ?
Is it ?
I suggest that we simply increase the medication
until things make sense .
Or maybe until I can get myself a new doctor .
Pardon ?
Since I 'm hallucinating and I can 't seem to remember things
you can help me with something .
Yeah . Inhale .
Did we have an affair ?
No .
Did you want to ?
Yes .
Did you think I wanted to ?
Then why didn 't we ?
Because you were married to the boss .
But I 'm not now .
I 'm here ... I 'm ...
I 'm trying to help you .
Why don 't you trust me ?
Because you can 't trust somebody when they think you 're crazy .
Phil .
Hello , Miranda .
I need to talk to you for a minute .
This is about Pete .
What about him , Miranda ?
I don 't think he 's the best doctor to be treating me .
Is your complaint about him on a personal level ?
Pete 's the best doctor I have on my staff now .
And he has my full support .
Now , if you 'll excuse me , Miranda .
- Miranda . - Hi , Teddy .
- How are they treating you ? - Like I 'm crazy , Teddy .
- They think I did it , but I didn 't do it . - All right . Thank you .
- I didn 't do it , Teddy . - Have a seat .
Let 's not ...
Let 's not talk about what you did or didn 't do , all right ?
What 's important is what I can do for you now .
Now , the DA is pushing for a hearing as early as next week .
Next week ? We haven 't even had time to investigate .
We can 't have a hearing next week .
As your attorney , I gotta tell you the evidence is overwhelming .
You 've been placed at the scene . The sheriff saw you driving home .
The neighbors heard the screams .
They 've got the murder weapon with your prints on it .
Your prints are on the floor , walls , everything .
Yeah , but what 's my motive ? I don 't have a motive , Teddy .
Why would I do that ? Maybe one of his ex-patients came .
Has anybody checked the files ? Has anybody escaped ?
That person would have a motive . I was there , and I would scream .
- Maybe I went into shock . - Miranda .
The only shot we have is to plead temporary insanity .
And I don 't even know if that 's gonna work . You 're a brilliant psychiatrist .
That will make jurors think " If she wanted to kill somebody
she could probably fake insanity and get away with it . "
I 'm not crazy .
- That 's the point . - No , the point is
I 'm the only one around here that believes I didn 't kill my husband !
Do you think I 'm crazy ?
That 's all right . Forget it .
Forget it .
Sheriff Ryan is here .
He 'd like to talk to you .
You know he was Doug 's best friend , so I 'd advise against it .
It 's fine , Teddy . I don 't have anything to hide .
Five minutes .
Hi , Bob .
Miranda .
I just have a few questions that we need to clear up .
When you first came in and he was sitting on the couch
the way we reconstruct the crime is that the first blow came from in front of him .
Which means he must have seen it coming .
And what we don 't understand is how he ...
- Why did you do it ? - Sheriff .
How could you kill Doug like that ? He loved you .
- That 's the only question I need answered . - You don 't have to answer any questions .
I don 't have any answers to the questions , Bob .
You don 't ? You better start thinking of some answers , because you 're in some trouble .
- Sheriff , that 's enough . That 's enough ! - No , no , no .
I need her to tell me why she did it .
Okay , we 're done . Enough !
Let 's kill your friend , see how you feel !
- You said no shock treatment . - Here 's some shock treatment !
- Stop it . Why would you take these out ? - Don 't look .
Don 't look at them .
I had to pick him up off the floor , Miranda . In pieces !
Miranda , what 's that ?
It 's okay . It 's okay , Miranda .
- Why are you doing this to me ? - Miranda , let 's just go . We 're done .
- Why are you doing this to me ? - It 's okay .
Why are you doing this to me ? Why are you doing this to me ? !
Come in , Miranda .
Please , take a seat .
So ...
You wanted to see me .
I was there .
I was there when Doug was killed .
But I wasn 't alone .
I wasn 't there alone , and that 's what " not alone " means .
- Who was there with you ? - I don 't know who it was .
I don 't know . I don 't know who it was .
But somebody else was there .
Miranda .
We know you have no family left .
We are your family now .
I know . I know you ... I know .
I want you to know that we 're gonna do everything we possibly can
to help you and to make you feel secure .
And to make you feel that you can trust us here .
But there 's a hearing scheduled .
- Miranda . Sit down . - Just ... Come on , sit down .
Miranda .
Who is this girl ?
- Put the picture back . - Who is this girl ?
That 's my daughter , Rachel .
No , this is the girl I saw at the bridge . This is the girl .
- No . - How is she ? Where is she ?
- It 's impossible . - This is the girl I 've been seeing .
This girl , right here .
She 's dead .
Rachel died four years ago .
I 'm a rational person .
I believe in science .
I don 't believe in the paranormal .
And I don 't believe in ghosts .
But if you are the ghost of Rachel Parsons
then you would let me out of this cell .
Bob , you leave this ?
Shit . Pete 's office .
Chloe .
Chloe !
Help me !
Let me go ! Let me go !
Check Chloe ! Check Chloe ! She needs help !
- Did you talk to Chloe ? - Yes .
- Was she raped ? - Was she raped ? No .
- Why ? - Did you check her ?
Did I ... ? She was checked . Of course she was checked .
- He didn 't have time . - He ?
- What about her face ? She had a cut . - She ran into a wall . She did that to herself .
I saw a tattoo . Did she talk about a tattoo ?
- Why don 't you sit down . A tattoo ? - Yeah , a tattoo .
A woman in flames , hands up like this :
Like a Biblical image .
The Anima Sola ?
- Yeah , the Anima Sola . That 's what I saw . - It 's a common archetypal image .
I mean , it 's the woman in chains , awaiting her fate .
I 'm talking about something I saw on the chest of a man .
- That 's what I saw . - You 're in crisis .
This image is tailor-made for your state of mind .
A woman in purgatory .
I need you to explain this to me , though .
- Rachel Parsons did not commit suicide . - She jumped off a bridge .
- When I saw her ... - She was washed downstream five miles .
- She was cut up . - You saw her ?
- Yes , I saw her . Someone did that to her ! - Police , newspapers , coroner are wrong ?
- Let 's reopen the case . - Maybe they should !
- I saw her . And she 's connected to me . - Delusions , hallucinations ...
- How , I don 't know . ... disorganized speech , incoherence ...
Don 't rattle off your psychiatric shit ! I know it like the back of my hand !
Good .
Saves me the trouble .
Glass cells are having electrical problems .
I 'm gonna transfer you to a Psych Ward cell .
One strike , you 're going to solitary .
Don 't screw up .
Rachel Parsons was there .
Dead or alive , I don 't know .
That girl came to me .
She came to me .
Hi , Chloe .
I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry I didn 't believe you .
I need you to tell me who did this to you .
Tell me his name , Chloe .
Chloe , tell me . Tell me anything . Tell me .
I 'll tell you one thing :
He can have my body
but he will never have my soul .
Never .
The devil .
It 's okay .
He said you 're next .
- Try to stay awake . - Yes , ma 'am .
If you need me , I 'll be in the coffee room .
Lights out .
Leave me alone !
- Doesn 't even look like a real ant . - It 's got disco balls for eyes .
- ' 50s B movies , man . - Giant bug movies are great .
Hey , what is that ?
It 's Dr. Grey . She 's trying to kill herself .
Level C , we 've got suicidal behavior in cell 33 . Sending backup .
Open it !
Dr. Grey 's in trouble !
Number 33 , open it now !
Oh , damn . Damn , what a mess .
- Hold her , I 'll medicate her . - What the hell for ? She 's already out .
Don 't argue with me .
Jesus ! Easy , easy . No , don 't hurt me .
Stop her ! She 's got my keys , stop her !
Shit !
Hey ! Hey !
Wait ! Hey !
We got a runner ! Inmate escaping ! Block Three !
- Stay with me . - All right .
She 's gone this way . Let 's go !
Clear !
Split up ! Keep moving !
She 's going up the North Tower !
Shit !
Hey ! It 's already open !
She 's on the upper level !
Hold it right there !
- Dr. Grey ! - We 're on Three , she 's heading for One !
Go ! Go !
Go the other way !
Circle back .
Come on , Hank .
Don 't think she made it to this building anyway .
Yeah , but even so , there 's no way she can get out .
Hide-and-seek . The longer it lasts , the more overtime we make .
- You should be a professor . - Professors always nail the pretty students .
Let 's go . I don 't think she 's in here .
I got it .
Is it clear there ?
We checked corridors Four and Five .
- It 's cool . We 're headed to Six and Seven . - Yeah . It 's Joe , up at the desk .
- What 's going on down there ? - Looks dark down there .
What do you mean , what do I mean ?
Look , this is the fourth time this month this has happened . Never mind .
- Ye ... Thank you . - Finally .
- Took long enough . - Shit .
Hey , Joe .
You see something ?
Yeah , just now when the monitors came on .
Corridor Six , something flashed in front of the camera .
Frank , East Wing . Don , take the West . I 'll take the stairs .
Here , take my car .
Go . Go .
Go on .
What do you want from me ? !
Okay . Now what ?
Miranda , no !
Doug ?
No . No , Miranda , no .
Miranda , don 't ! No , don 't , please !
Please ! No ! Miranda , no ! No , please !
Please ! Don 't do this to me ! No !
Don 't ! No ! Miranda , no , wait !
Don 't do this to me , please , Miranda !
Miranda , no ! Don 't ! No !
Don 't do this to me , Miranda ! Miranda , please !
I love you .
What did I do ?
Why ?
Why me ?
Why ? Why ?
Willow Creek .
How was Willow Creek ?
This rain is slowing the work down . It 's a big damn mess .
I 'll see you in a couple of days .
It 's good to be God .
I love you .
- Drop the knife ! - Drop the gun !
Put it on the ground now !
- Drop the gun ! - Drop the knife !
- You drop it ! - Holy Christ .
What ?
Help me , please !
Help !
Carter , get down here now !
Help me , please !
Please !
All I can tell you is that the girl has been identified as Tracy Seavers .
She was reported missing two weeks ago .
She was found this morning by two patrolmen in Willow Creek
at a farm belonging to Dr. Douglas Grey . She is now hospitalized .
Can she speak ? Has she told you anything ?
- We can 't comment on that . - Are there others ?
We can 't confirm that . Excuse me .
Sheriff , is the FBI taking over this investigation ?
Why don 't you ask the goddamn FBI ?
We need her at the hospital for medication .
Consider house arrest pending trial , given the circumstances .
Last night , your client dropped a guard
assaulted a nurse , escaped from an institution , stole a car ...
And saved a girl 's life .
- How did she know she was there ? - I don 't know .
- But the point is ... - The woman is still a murder suspect !
Come here .
The FBI says there could be more victims .
There were needles down there , a video camera .
Once the press gets ahold of it , it 'll get big and ugly .
Now , I need some answers , and I 'm running out of time .
So your client isn 't going anywhere until my team ...
I need to talk to her .
It 's hard to believe Doug did something like this .
We worked together a long time . I thought I knew him pretty well .
How could I be so blind ?
Well , you weren 't the only one , Phil .
Do you think my daughter could also have been a victim of Doug 's ?
Yes .
That 's what " not alone " means .
Rachel was trying to tell me that she was not Doug 's only victim .
And all this time
we thought our baby had committed suicide .
You see
even after she was gone ...
Well ...
What ?
I had this recurring dream about her .
Eventually I took medication to block it out .
What kind of dream ?
She was burning in flames , in terrible pain .
I couldn 't save her .
I saw her exactly the same way , burning in flames .
What does that mean ?
Miranda , I ... I ...
I wouldn 't look for a real-world explanation .
It 's a dream , a delusion .
A delusion that we both seem to share .
- Yeah . - Pete .
I was just talking to Parsons .
I 've been wrong about everything until now .
It 's finally clear to me . The image is finally clear .
The man raping women in prison is connected to the murders .
It goes back to the Anima Sola tattoo .
Miranda , you have to stop doing this . Do you understand me ?
Every time people start taking you seriously , you start talking about delusions again .
I 'm not deluded , Pete , I 'm possessed .
I don 't believe in ghosts .
Neither do I , but they believe in me .
Great , just great .
Let 's go . Come on .
I need to talk to Sheriff Ryan .
He 's working with the FBI team . He won 't be back tonight .
It 's really important .
I 'll leave him a message .
Thank you .
Screw it .
I got a message you wanted to talk to me ?
Yeah , Bob .
I wanna talk to you . Maybe this time you can actually hear me .
Because the last time , all you wanted to do was scream and yell and accuse me ...
- Is this what you wanna talk to me about ? - No . I wanna talk about the facts .
They 're a little different now , right ?
Do you have any idea what happens to a small-town sheriff when the FBI takes over ?
- Lf you know anything , anything ... - Not alone .
What ?
Not alone .
I know what it means .
There are two killers .
Parsons and I both saw a girl burning in flames .
Then I saw Chloe being raped by a man with an Anima Sola tattoo on his body .
A woman burning in flames . Get it ?
Okay , it 's crazy . I know it sounds crazy . Pete has told me it 's crazy .
- You told Pete ? When ? - Yes .
Yes .
This afternoon . Why ?
I don 't think you 're crazy at all . And I don 't know why he would dismiss it .
- You actually saw this tattoo ? - Yes , I saw it . On a man .
I 've heard of serial killers who hunt together .
Classic mentor and disciple syndrome .
So we 're looking for the disciple ? Who could it be ?
- I don 't know . - You 're a psychiatrist .
What kind of guy would this have to be ?
Okay .
He would have to be someone who grew up in a household
that had an absent father .
He developed
an obsessive , over-dependent relationship with his mother
which then turned into some inappropriate sexual attraction .
He probably even got off torturing little animals as a kid .
And as a man he is totally confused about his sexuality .
That 's who he is .
Man , that 's screwed up .
But a guy like that could seem smart and normal , right ?
Yeah , they usually do . Yeah .
Look , Miranda , I don 't wanna scare you
but if there is a second killer out there , he is frantically trying to cover his trail .
You 're a big threat to this guy . Who knows how much more you know ?
I don 't know anything else .
You saw the tattoo , found the girl at the barn .
Yeah , but I found all that by instinct .
This guy is facing the electric chair .
He doesn 't have the luxury of believing in instinct or ghosts .
He 's gotta believe that Doug confessed to you what he was doing .
But he didn 't confess .
Maybe he didn 't spill it out loud , but ...
Well , you know , you 're a psychiatrist .
There 's a lot of ways to confess .
I 'm just trying to put myself in this guy 's place .
Then why didn 't he go back to Willow Creek ?
- Take care of the girl , clean up evidence ? - Yeah .
Well , that 's how you get caught . You panic .
Better to let the dust settle .
But about you
he 's desperate . - Yeah ?
Desperate enough to
talk to me ?
Well , you 're right .
I do fit the profile .
Longtime friend of Doug 's , access to the prison .
I never did get a kick out of torturing animals , though .
Stop it !
- No ! - Yes !
- You can 't kill me ! - I 'm not gonna kill you .
After this kicks in , I 'm gonna have a lot more fun with you than Doug ever did .
Help !
Miranda !
Damn it !
Help me ! Help !
Help me !
Okay .
You tried to escape , Miranda .
That means I can do whatever I want to you .
Rachel wasn 't the first , you know .
Doug killed a girl when he was 15 years old !
I helped him bury the body .
What are best friends for ?
We got older . But I gotta tell you
you never lose your taste for the young girls .
Then we stopped for a long time .
But then Dougie saw sweet Rachel and ...
That was an itch way too deep not to scratch .
And then we had the time of our lives out at Willow Creek .
Everything was perfect .
Those girls would do anything .
We were their god .
Until you ...
Miranda !
You and I both know you 're not getting out of here .
So let 's be logical
and end this thing .
Thank you , Miranda .
Rachel ?
This isn 't logical .
You 're already dead !
Logic is overrated .
I 'm sorry , Miranda .
So it 's been almost a year and I still have bad dreams .
Sometimes I wake up screaming .
That 's normal .
No , not these dreams .
Everyone thought you and I were crazy
but we were seeing the truth .
More than they could see .
Once you open the door , you can never close it .
Not true . I closed it .
Then I locked it
and then I threw away the key .
I really hope that 's true .
You know , my train leaves in half an hour .
Okay . I 'll get you on your way .
So good luck with your job , okay ?
I wanted to thank you for what you did .
You really helped me .
You helped me .
You taught me how to listen .
Thank you .
We made it .
No !